# **Douglas Pleger**

# Full-Stack Developer | Renton, WA 707.803.3646 | <u>DougPleger@gmail.com</u> Portfolio.stamplayapp.com | Linkedin.com/in/douglaspleger

### **About Me**

Full-stack developer with a strong, passionate creative side. Highly focused, strong-willed and will never turn down an opportunity to help my team and company. Years of experience in communicating and working with others in fast-paced environments. Hoping to continue honing and expanding my programming experience as the industry grows and changes.

# **Technical Tookit**

Front-End: HTML/CSS, jQuery, HTTP Request/Response, AJAX, ARIA, MS Accessibility tools

Languages: JavaScript, Python, Ruby

Frameworks: Django, Rails, Express.js, Socket.io, Bootstrap, AngularJS

Version Control: Git, GitHub, Cloud9, STAMPlay

Databases: SQL(MySQL, Sqlite, PostgresSQL), NoSQL(MongoDB), Mongoose.js, ActiveRecords

Adobe Suite: Flash, PhotoShop, Illustrator, Acrobat

# **Education**

#### Coding Dojo - Bellevue, WA

Completed an intensive web development program covering multiple languages; spanning more than 1000 hours of active programming. Learned RESTful practices and worked closely with fellow students to create complex, real-world applications.

#### Self-Directed Education

Udacity(Coder's Manual), CodeCademy, W3Schools, StackSocial, Mozilla Developer Network

# Employment History

# Pro Sports Club, Facility Operations | Bellevue, WA | October 2014 – October 2015

Worked overnight with a small team to provide routine maintenance to keep our fitness institution in top pristine quality. Focus on detail, efficiency and communication was needed to ensure us meeting the pedigree of the Pro Club name.

#### Zones Inc, Customer Service/Credit Entry | Auburn, WA | March 2012 - September 2014

Provided multiple-administrative roles: tracking and crediting returns, handling and correcting clerical errors and working with our shipping providers to track lost and missing shipments. Communicated between our sales force, warehouses and clients to ensure strong, seamless exchanges. Helped integrate new Microsoft Dynamics (AX) platform and created training materials necessary to train new overseas employees.

#### Nintendo of America, Tier-2 Wireless Tech Support | Redmond, WA | October 2010 – February 2012

Provided over-the-phone technical support to customers wishing to connect their Nintendo products online. Used concise communication skills to help anyone from younger children and elderly alike to identify wireless router products, make any necessary security or connectivity changes and ensure customer satisfaction. Provided detailed data-surveys upon each call. Recorded calls were used as positive examples in training classes.